The newest attorney at the world's most powerful law firm has
never lost a case. But he's about to lose his soul.
The Devil's Advocate is a drama, mystery, horror
film directed by Taylor Hackford.
Aspiring Florida defense lawyer Kevin Lomax
accepts a job at a New York law firm.
With the stakes getting higher every case, Kevin quickly learns
that his boss has something far more evil planned.
Kevin Lomax, played by Keanu Reeves.
John Milton, played by Al Pacino.
Mary Ann Lomax, played by Charlize Theron.
Eddie Barzoon, played by Jeffrey Jones.
Mrs. Lomax, played by Judith Ivey.
Christabella, played by Connie Nielsen.
Devil's Advocate is a 1997 American supernatural horror film directed by Taylor Hackford, written by
Jonathan Lemkin and Tony Gilroy, and starring Keanu Reeves, Al Pacino and Charlize Theron.
Based on Andrew Neiderman's 1990 novel, it is about a gifted young Florida
lawyer invited to work for a major New York City law firm.
As his wife becomes haunted by frightening visions, the lawyer slowly
realizes that the firm's owner, John Milton, is the Devil.
The name John Milton is one of several allusions to Paradise Lost, as well
as to Dante Alighieri's Inferno and the legend of Faust.
An adaptation of Neiderman's novel went into a development hell during the
1990s, with Hackford gaining control of the production.
Filming took place around New York City and Florida.
Devil's Advocate received mixed reviews, with critics crediting it
for entertainment value and Pacino's performance.
It grossed $153 million at the box office and won the
Saturn Award for Best Horror Film.
It also became the subject of the copyright lawsuit Hart v.
Warner Bros., Inc.
for its visual art.
The film explores themes of child abuse, southern
usa, marriage crisis, obsession, bible.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.